SUMUKH

VASISHT SHANKAR

Address:

1436/1, 6th Cross, Krishnamurthy Puram, Mysore-570004

Phone:

+91 8880478748

Email:

sumukhmys1999@gmail.com

Github:

www.github.com/sumukh-vasisht

Website:

https://svs.codes/

LinkedIn:

https://in.linkedin.com/in/sumukh -vasisht-s/

Skill Highlights

- Project management
- Strong decision maker
- Complex problem solver
- Team Player

Technical Skills

Data Science:

Matplotlib Seaborn
Plotly mpld3
Apache Spark Hadoop
SQL MongoDB

Statistics

Programming:

C C++

Python JavaScript HTML/CSS Vue.Js

Tools and Technologies:

Github

Summary

Team oriented individual with superb communication abilities. Final year undergraduate student at The National Institute of Engineering, Mysore. Offering exceptional programming, statistical analysis, and research abilities to extract, clean, and prepare data for data science model ingestion and data visualization.

Education

Bachelor of Engineering

The National Institute of Engineering, Mysore Bachelor of Engineering in Information Science Anticipated Graduation: June 2021 CGPA: 9.02/10.0 (Six Semesters)

Experience

• Software Engineering Intern – 01/2021 to Present FICO, Bangalore

Currently working on a product called the FICO Studio. Using the Java Springboot framework and the AWS Cloud Technology.

- Al Engineer 08/2020 to 12/2020
- Research Intern 02/2020 to 07/2020
 Antriksh Labs Pvt. Ltd., Mysore

Worked part time as a Research Intern and then as an AI Engineer at Antriksh Labs, Mysore, where contributed towards the development of Data Visualization Pipeline and Statistical analysis of data. Used technologies and languages like Python, Spark, Hadoop, SQL, D3, Apache ECharts, etc.

Sumedh S Vijay, CEO & Co-Founder, Antriksh Labs Pvt. Ltd.

Email ID: sumedh@antrikshlabs.space

• Software Intern - 03/2019 to 10/2019
Deshik Labs, Mysore

Contributed to the development of PWAs and websites for different clients. Was involved in the whole Software Development Life-cycle. Used technologies like Python-Flas, HTML/CSS, Vue.JS, Google Firebase, Bootstrap, etc. Shreesha Ramaswamy, Founder, Deshik Labs Email ID: shreesha@deshik.in

Projects

Data Visualization and Statistics Computation of Datasets

 Data Visualization Pipeline (March 2020 – Dec 2020)
 The pipeline involves data cleaning, computing statistics,
 Visualizing the dataset by various kinds of plots through matplotlib, seaborn, mpld3, e-charts, etc., implementing different ML models on the dataset and Exploratory
 Data Analysis.

SUMUKH

VASISHT SHANKAR

Organizations

1. IEEE

Active IEEE member form the past 3 years.

 NIE IEEE Student Branch (Student Branch of IEEE at NIE)

> Coordinated with RPs for numerous workshops and tech talks. Coordinated Industrial Visits to CISCO and DELL EMC.

3. **U&I**

Working as an active volunteer at the NGO aimed at imparting quality education for underprivileged kids.

4. techNIEks'20

Volunteered as a convener for the website development team for our college fest in 2020.

Achievements

- Presented a paper and published an article at 'International Conference of Human-Wildlife Conflict Mitigation'
- 2. AIR 2 in RIE CEE
- 3. Lead a team and presented findings on 'Medicinal uses of soil' at National Children Science Congress.
- Won numerous prizes at state and national level quiz and debate contests.

- 2. Identification of Social Issues of India through Analysis of Twitter Data (September 2020 Jan 2020): An analytics platform aimed at identification of social issues which the Indian citizens face on a day-to-day basis. Tweets mined from Twitter is classified into complaints and non-complaints and are categorized accordingly by ML models, which is then displayed on a dashboard. Built using Python Flask, Sklearn, pandas, tweepy, matplotlib, HTML/CSS, Bulma
- 3. Tweet Analyzer (April 2020): NLP based web app which scraps data off twitter and analyzes sentiments of the tweets including those of COVID-19. Built with HTML/CSS and Python tweepy, pandas, textblob, re (Link: www.github.com/sumukh-vasisht/twitterWeb)
- 4. Self-Checkout System (March 2020 August 2020): IoT based self-checkout system for shopping centers. Built using Raspberry Pi, Python, Firebase, HTML/CSS and JavaScript.
- 5. Cric-Predicc (September 2019 October 2019)
 Data Analytics Project which predicts the winner of a cricket match. Coded using Python sklearn, keras.
 (Link: www.github.com/sumukh-vasisht/CricPredict)
- 6. VCast Foundry App (March 2019 July 2019) An operations and management application for a casting industry, called VCast in Mysore, built using Framework7 with Vue, VueJS, HTML/CSS, JavaScript, Node.JS, Firebase and Firestore.

All my other projects can be found in my github repository

Certifications

- 1. Machine Learning: Stanford University
- 2. Neural Networks and Deep Learning: deeplearning.ai
- 3. Data Science using Python: Michigan University

Extra-Curricular Activities

- SAC Coordinator (June, 2019 July, 2020), Digital Design Lead and Student Branch Networking Coordinator (2018-19) at NIE IEEE Student Branch
- 2. Part of the team which organized NIE Summer of Code 6.0.
- 3. Conducted various workshops and sessions on Machine Learning, Game Development, competitive coding, etc.
- 4. Hosted many inter colligate competitive coding competitions.
- 5. Conducted Focus Group Sessions on Web Development.
- 6. Pianist, guitarist and singer in the college band 'Swayam'.